(upbeat music)
- I'm Khadija from HISP: Tanzania.
- My name is Zeferino
Saugene, I'm from Mozambique.
- My name is John Lewis
from HISP: Vietnam.
- My role is as a system analyst,
but as well as a teachers
to implement that.
- I am coordinating the team
a foreign community that told
us is Mozambique, which is
also called and so Digitas.
- I'm a director now for his
Vietnam leading the adjust
to implementation in Southeast
Asia and Pacific Islands.
- I heard about DHIS2 when I
was in my university studies,
started engaging myself,
went around asked about it,
and at least they were cooperative enough,
shared me the link, DHIS2 to fundamentals.
And I started to learn more about it.
And I would say everything
started from there.
- I think started I getting
involved with this group in 2003
in the master program.
And then I went to Oslo in August,
stayed there for one year.
And then we come back to Mozambique
and then I had one hour field work
and then start writing and
then finalize it in 2005.
- 2000 When I was interviewed
for as a software developer
to join his India project and
one of the small constancy
in India.
So I was appointed as a
system developer for DHIS21.
- As the DHIS2 team,
we managed to support
our ministry of health
in implementing the DHIS2 country-wise
and it's the key system that
is used to by the minister
of health in Tanzania in data collection
and of course boarding.
- The DHIS, I'm a conference
is the event where we,
there is a lot of sharing experience,
and then a lot of users,
implementers, donors,
they attend then we get there
and then we share all our experience
from the implementation side.
And also from the user perspective.
- When we started HISP
India I was the only person
and then like three group
to the national level
for the entire country.
I guess that that was
the key event for me.
We take a small NGO operating
in a very small constancy
in one particular village to
move to the national entity
and working with the
Indian ministry of health.
- A lot, honestly speaking,
because since I've started using it,
or since I started knowing about it,
it has proved to be a very
very flexible platform.
It was initially aimed just
for health information systems.
We managed to extend beyond healthy,
but even using it in agriculture
sector, as well as water.
So I would say it's a
very flexible platform
and it can support a number of use cases.
As we have had different use
cases from different countries,
- HISP is a family we have
been supporting many countries
and then when I get to know several people
they share the same challenges.
For example, as in
Mozambique, then we will,
we go and we find that same
challenge and you find that you
will also find it in countries
like the Guinea-Bissau
or Sao Tome.
So it has been to me it is
a community., it's a family.
- For me, it's an ideology,
which basically thinks about
how best we can try to use
informal system in the health
settings and how best we can
try to get the right tool
to white people and DHIS2
what we believe is a tool which helps
the health administrators and people
to make a decision at the local level.
And as well as the national level.
(upbeat music)