(soft music)
- [Narrator] One of the
most essential features
of DHIS2 is its capability to transform
and review the raw data users enter
into the platform into different
data visualization outputs.
In this video, we will review examples
of how to visualize
data using Pivot tables,
Charts, Maps and Reports.
Let's see how it works.
Let's say we are reviewing
child vaccination program
and want to know how
many children received
their tuberculosis vaccine or BCG dose
during the last 12 months in
each district of the country.
To get started select the Data
visualizer app within DHIS2.
From this app select Pivot
tables as the visualization type.
From the available drop down menus
first select the data you want to see.
In this example BCG doses given.
Then the timeframe of those data,
in this case, the last 12 months,
and the locations where
those data belong to,
for example all districts in the country.
If you want to change the layout
simply drag and drop the parameters
to rearrange the request.
In just a couple of clicks,
you are able to get a summary
of children immunized with BCG by district
Within the last 12 months.
You can save this pivot
table to use it later.
What if you want to view
these data in a chart?
Simply select the type of
chart and rearrange the layout.
If you are not sure about the
best type of chart to use,
you will find short descriptions
of each one to help you select
the best fit for your needs.
You can also visualize the data on a map
by selecting the map option
from the chart type menu.
You can add different
types of layers to the map
to add more information to the output.
All these examples show very simple uses
of the data visualization
tools available in DHIS2.
You can also create more complex outputs
using the same tools.
For example, if you look at this chart
you will see that it shows
the overall performance
of delivering essential
vaccines per region
compared to an expected target.
And more importantly,
you can add descriptions
and interpretations
to these outputs based
on the data being shown.
This allows you to
provide a bit more context
to the data that you are displaying.
You can give this output a name
and add a description that
explains what you are measuring.
For example, "if BCG
coverage is greater than 90%
that means that we should
sustain the efforts as they are."
Low coverage can be based
on many different factors
that we can explain here.
You can also add an interpretation based
on your analysis of the data shown.
For example, "in Cat
District EPI MR 2 is 52.2%.
Have we checked to see
if there is an issue with
stock or service delivery?"
Finally, DHIS2 provides
several reporting tools
through the Reports app.
For example, we can
use the Data Set Report
to obtain detailed information
about different aspects of
the immunization program
in a given health facility,
in a specific period.
In summary, we have seen how
to create different types
of outputs in DHIS2 based
on the data already entered.
Pivot tables, charts
and maps can be created
in just a couple of clicks and a number
of report types are available
within the reports app.
We can also add
descriptions to the outputs
and interpretations based
on our analysis of the data.
(soft music)