(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] DHIS2 isn't
just a piece of software.
It is made up of applications, resources,
different organizations,
and most importantly people.
So let's take a look
at how you can interact
with the different parts
of the DHIS2 ecosystem.
Let's start with the research
of the health information systems program
at the university of Oslo, HISP UiO.
HISP was founded to strengthen
health information systems
in developing countries.
To support this goal,
the group researches,
the broader ecosystem of
health information systems.
This includes their materials, people,
competencies, institutions, and practices.
You can get involved in a
HISP-led academic program
or take part in their
action research projects.
The HISP UiO research program
also includes the DHIS2 design lab,
which explores how researchers
and practitioners working
within the DHIS2 software ecosystem
can facilitate the design
and innovation of tools
that provide value to
the work of end users.
In addition to HISP UiO,
there is a global network of HISP groups,
staffed and led by DHIS2 experts.
They provide implementation support,
assist with platform customization,
develop innovative solutions
and build capacity through
the DHIS2 academy program
and local training efforts.
As you get more involved with DHIS2,
you'll likely want to learn
more about what others are doing
with their implementations,
share details of your own implementation,
or just ask for help.
The DHIS2 Community of Practice
is the discussion platform
where you can interact
with other practitioners
and learn from each other.
As you start to use DHIS2,
you may want to check the functionality
of a particular application.
The DHIS2 documentation
contains detailed information
and implementation considerations
available for DHIS2.
And it's written by a core
team of DHIS2 experts.
These guides are all
available at docs.dhis2.org.
As DHIS2 is open source,
you can find all of its
source code inside GitHub.
You can also find all of
the DHIS2 documentation
and you can help us improve it
by suggesting changes or additions.
Being a global public good means
that DHIS2 needs to be available
for users all over the world.
Translation of user interface elements
and messages for the core software,
including applications,
metadata and other elements
is the key part of DHIS2 localization.
To facilitate a community-driven
global translation effort,
DHIS2 uses the Transifex platform.
You can view and contribute
to DHIS2 translations
and Transifex at translate.dhis2.org.
If you want to develop your DHIS2 skills,
you can take a DHIS2 academy course.
The academy program includes both online
and in-person courses on both general
and specialized topics.
Attending an academy will
help build your skills
to support DHIS2 implementations
and allow you to interact
with DHIS2 experts.
If you want to explore DHIS2 features
and practice your skills,
you can try it out on a
demo version of DHIS2.
You can find the latest
demo at play.dhis2.org.
As you use DHIS2, you might find
that something does not
work as it is supposed to
or you might even think of a new feature.
In the DHIS2 Jira,
you can notify the
software development group
at HISP UiO and they will look into it.
If you are interested in
developing applications for DHIS2,
make sure you have a look at
the DHIS2 developer portal.
Here you will find the latest information
about DHIS2 application development tools,
tips and training events.
You can find links to all the parts
of the ecosystem directly on
the DHIS2 website, dhis2.org.
The website acts as a hub
where you can find useful information
on the latest updates on DHIS2
including software downloads,
plus links to all of the
resources mentioned in this video.
You can also get all the latest updates
by signing out for the DHIS2 newsletter,
and by following DHIS2
on Twitter and Facebook.
Above all, DHIS2 is a community
driven project that has succeeded
through local innovation
and collaboration across
countries in the Global South.
There are many ways to get involved
whether you are a DHIS2 user, implementer,
developer or researcher.
Take a look around the DHIS2 ecosystem
and join the global community.
(gentle upbeat music)