(soft music)
- [Narrator] In a small village in Africa,
a community health worker administers
a patient's first vaccination.
In a remote settlement, treatment arrives
just as a disease
outbreak starts to spread.
In rural Asia, a midwife
shares vital nutrition
and health information
with an expecting mother.
In the Middle East, health workers provide
medical care in refugee camps.
Moments like these save
lives, but coordinating them
on a national or global
scale requires resources,
planning, and above all, information.
How do you ensure the right
data's captured, analyzed,
and made available to inform
decisions that make an impact?
(music continues)
DHIS2 can help.
(orchestral music)
DHIS2 brings together
a wide variety of data
from a large number of
sources to one central system,
allowing for better planning,
information sharing,
and decision-making at all levels.
From the Minister of Health to regional
and district managers, to
medical workers in the field,
everyone can use this information
to make an impact on people's lives.
We'll show you how DHIS2
captures information
from even the most
remote offline locations,
as well as making it easier
to submit standard forms
and aggregate reports, and
you'll see how captured data is
reviewed, analyzed, and shared,
all from a single opensource platform.
Let's see an example of DHIS2 in action.
The Ministry of Health has planned
a nationwide immunization campaign.
At each community health
center across the country,
thousands of people will be vaccinated.
Before each center closes,
a community health worker
uses their tablet to
enter the doses given.
When internet is available,
the health worker's notified
and the data is sent to
the central DHIS2 database.
From her office in the city,
the regional health manager
can see, at a glance, how many
vaccines were administered
in each community and the
immunization rate for her region.
And at the Ministry of
Health, DHIS2 dashboards
measure the campaign's progress
and highlights any areas
of concern that need to be addressed.
Now let's see how DHIS2 can help respond
to disease outbreaks.
A nationwide DHIS2 map shows
an increase in reported cases
of potentially deadly virus.
Health workers are dispatched
to the remote village
at the center of the outbreak,
but without internet access,
how will they be able to
transmit new data back
to update the national authorities?
With DHIS2, the emergency worker can count
how many households and
individuals are impacted
by the disease and send
the data directly by SMS.
At the Ministry of Health,
the emergency coordinator
can monitor the outbreak response
using her DHIS2 dashboard
and decide what followup actions to take.
In reality, there can
be millions of records
and thousands of datasets
being captured and sent
to a single DHIS2 database.
Paper forms have their limits.
DHIS2 makes it easy to
collect the same datasets
on Android phones and tablets,
and desktop computers,
and even submit limited data by SMS.
Data submitted to DHIS2 is instantly saved
and can be accessible
from any connected device.
DHIS2 provides data collection
in even the most remote
and fragile settings where internet
and electricity may not be reliable.
Making important decisions
does not only depend
on how fast data's available,
it also depends on the quality
of the information available.
DHIS2 has many data quality
features that help ensure
that data is accurate before
it's used to make a decision.
These include the
ability to validate data,
identify duplicate entries,
and flag abnormal values for review.
Managers can see an audit
trail of all entries
and changes and review summary reports.
Once data is validated,
it's ready to be analyzed.
Using DHIS2, teams can
make sense of the data
by creating visualizations
such as charts, tables
and maps, and use filters to drill down
to the most important information.
They can even create custom
dashboards that can be shared
with other team members for
discussion and decision-making.
(music ends)
Whether you're planning a
nationwide immunization program,
building your capacity to respond
to deadly disease outbreaks,
overseeing national and
international programs
for ongoing epidemics, or
managing a complex project that
relies on data-driven decisions,
DHIS2 is a free opensource
tool that can improve
your impact, helping you
collect, analyze, share,
and transform your data
into information for action.
(orchestral music)