(gentle upbeat music)
- [Narrator] What happens
when you are entering data
into DHIS2, but your
internet connection is lost?
This can be a common problem in places
with limited or unstable
internet connectivity.
For this reason, DHIS2 has been built
with basic offline data
entry capabilities in mind
so you can continue to enter data
even when temporarily offline.
Let's take a look at how it works.
When you open the DHIS2 data entry app,
the message, You are
online, should display
in a yellow text box at
the top of the screen.
This means that you are
connected to the internet
and the data you entered
will be automatically saved
to the DHIS2 server.
Now, let's see what happens
if you lose internet access.
You can test this by turning
your internet connection off,
and then opening up a Data Entry form
and starting to enter data.
The message, You are offline,
data will be stored locally,
will appear at the top of the screen.
You'll notice that when you enter data,
the field still turns green
to indicate the data value is saved.
This is because the data
are being stored locally
on your computer's cache.
Let's turn the internet back on.
When the internet comes back on,
you will get another message that says,
There is data stored locally,
please upload to the server,
with an Upload button next to the message.
All you need to do is simply
click on the Upload button
and then you should receive the message,
Upload to server was successful.
It is critical that you do
not clear your browser cache
using the DHIS2 Browser Cache Cleaner app
until you have uploaded
your data to the server,
as your data are stored locally
in your DHIS2 browser cache.
Clearing your cache
before uploading your data
will result in data loss.
Note that the offline functionality
in the web-based DHIS2 data entry app
is intended to cover
periodic internet outages
and not to perform as a
permanent offline mode.
If you need to capture data in an area
where internet connectivity
is very limited,
or if you will be working temporarily
from an area with no
internet access at all,
we recommend using the
DHIS2 Android Capture app.
You will learn more about the Android app
later in this course.
To recap, in this video,
you have learned that DHIS2
allows you to enter data
when the internet connection is not stable
by saving the data locally
in your browser cache.
You will know when you are offline
by a message displayed on the screen.
When connectivity is restored,
you need to select a
button to upload the data
to the DHIS2 server.
(gentle upbeat music)