(lively music)
- [Instructor] It's
impossible to talk about DHIS2
without mentioning the HISP
program and HISP groups.
But what exactly is a HISP group
and how are they related to DHIS2?
In this video, we will
provide an overview.
Let's start with the original
Health Information Systems
Programme, or HISP,
which developed version one
of the DHIS software in
post-Apartheid South Africa in 1994
as a collaboration between
the University of Oslo
and the University of Western Cape.
HISP has since become a global movement
to strengthen health
information systems worldwide
as DHIS2 experts, many of whom
are former UiO PhD students
have gone on to found and lead HISP groups
in Africa, Asia and the Americas.
These HISP groups offer long-term support
to country governments
on DHIS2 implementation
and maintenance, provide capacity building
through the DHIS2 Academy program
and work with countries and organizations
to adapt DHIS2 systems
and create innovative
solutions to meet local needs.
HISP groups, together with HISP UiO,
form a global network of partners
that share common values,
including open-source principles,
local ownership, sustainability,
transparency and empowering data use.
While each group operates independently,
the HISP network as a whole collaborates
in a variety of ways.
In keeping with DHIS2's academic origins,
a primary area of HISP
collaboration is research.
Working with the information
systems research group
at HISP UiO, HISP groups engage
in action research,
uncovering best practices
through targeted country interventions
and deep dives.
They assess and evaluate
country DHIS2 implementations,
explore new domains and challenges
and document their findings for input
into global products and strategies.
Another key area of collaboration
is the ongoing development
of the DHIS2 platform.
While software development
is led by HISP UiO,
the HISP groups are the
most important source
of requirements for software
features and field testing
of DHIS2 releases due to their close work
with country governments.
Their input and feedback is essential
to ensuring that DHIS2 continues
to meet local needs and
function in local contexts.
HISP groups are also a
source of local innovations,
such as custom applications,
metadata configurations,
and modifications to the core platform,
developed to rapidly solve
specific country challenges.
These local solutions are shared
throughout the network and can be adapted
by the core team at HISP
UiO for global deployment,
followed by iterative improvements based
on further feedback from HISP groups based
on real-world experiences.
One example of a local innovation
becoming a global resource
was the HISP network's response
to the COVID-19 pandemic.
A DHIS2 program for
port-of-entry screening
and contact tracing
developed by HISP Sri Lanka
became the basis for a metadata package
quickly deployed in almost 40 countries
for the COVID-19 response.
HISP groups also worked together
in regional hubs on national,
multi-country and regional
DHIS2 system architecture,
implementation, research and
capacity building projects
in collaboration with HISP UiO.
In addition to this cycle of collaboration
between HISP groups in
the field and HISP UiO,
individual members from
various HISP groups also serve
as members of core DHIS2 teams
where they directly
contribute to development
of global metadata packages,
applications and training materials.
HISP, the Health Information
Systems Programme,
was the origin of the DHIS2 software
and HISP groups have
been the driving force
in developing DHIS2 from a local solution
into the world's largest
health information management system.
They provide long-term implementation
and maintenance support,
conduct capacity building,
perform information system
research and assessments,
provide input and feedback
on software releases,
develop and share local innovations,
and ensure that DHIS2
continues to meet local needs.
HISP groups are not just
a part of the DHIS2 story.
They are the foundation
of DHIS2's history.
Without HISP groups,
there would be no DHIS2.
(lively music)