(bright upbeat music)
- [Instructor] So far,
we have seen how data
are captured in DHIS2
for aggregate events and tracker models,
and how those data are verified
to ensure data quality.
We have also seen how
entered data are transformed
into different data visualization outputs,
such as pivot tables, charts, and maps,
and also how to obtain automatic reports
based on those data.
In this video, we will see
how these different
outputs and other elements
can be put together in a Dashboard,
where all relevant information
about a given program
can be shown and shared with other users
to make dissemination of data easier.
Typically, when you first log in to DHIS2,
you see what we refer to as the Dashboard.
The Dashboard is the page
where you will find a
collection of various outputs,
such as charts, maps and pivot
tables created within DHIS2.
You will find different
dashboards available
that you can move between
using the Dashboard Menu.
The dashboards that each user sees
are completely customizable,
and it's a very useful tool
to disseminate information
in a secured manner regarding
specific topics and outputs.
For example, here, you can
see an immunization dashboard
that contains maps that show information
about vaccine coverage.
Note that the intuitive color legend
immediately gives us information
about program performance
and identifies regions that perform well
compared to those that need improvement.
You can also take a map
and quickly convert it
to a chart or a table
directly in the dashboard.
This feature allows you to move
between charts, maps and tables
for any of the outputs
located on the dashboard.
If you want to open an
object in the dashboard
to further investigate the
data, you can do so easily.
The data that are shown
in a user's dashboard
depends on their own level of access.
For example, a user with
permissions to view data
within an entire country
will see more aggregated
on a given dashboard
than another user who can only view data
from a single district.
You can also view the descriptions
and interpretations of the outputs
which help in describing
what the outputs represent.
If you want to make a comment
about those interpretations,
you can easily do so from the same page.
As you can see, this
feature makes it possible
to share findings among the
users within your system
and discuss further
actions to be implemented
This is one way DHIS2
allows you to transform data
into information that can
support decision-making.
In summary, a dashboard
is a collection of outputs
that provides a summary of related topics
to be reviewed together.
They are very useful to
disseminate information
in a secured manner with other users
and can facilitate a
discussion of their analysis,
allowing for the sharing
of their interpretations of the data.
These discussions can support
the decision-making process
which is the final purpose of DHIS2,
transforming information into action.
(ambient music)