(bright music)
- [Instructor] In this video,
we'll show you how to use the key features
of the DHIS2 online Academy platform.
Once you've logged into the Academy
and selected your course,
you'll be greeted with the course page.
Right below the course title,
you'll see any messages
from the course team.
Then you will see the course menu
where you can click on a module
to view the subsections and units
or expand all to view the
outline of the entire course.
You can start the course
by selecting a unit
from the course overview
or by selecting the start course button
in the top right corner.
If you've already begun,
you'll instead see the
resume course button.
Every time you log in,
you'll launch at the
subsection you were last in.
Once in, you'll have the
detailed course overview
on the left, next to the course material.
The blue underscored subsection
is where you currently are.
You can move between the course content
using the previous and next buttons
at the top and bottom of the page.
If you've completed a unit,
you'll see a green check mark.
To answer knowledge check
questions or graded quizzes,
you'll need to select the answer
and click the submit button.
When the show answer button is enabled,
you can click on it to
check the right answer.
At the very top of the page,
you'll find additional tabs
related to your course.
The most important is the progress tab
where you can check on
how you're getting on
through the course.
The FAQ tab is where you'll
find answers to common questions
about things like grading and
getting course certificates.
Finally, you'll find
the participant's guide,
which gives a detailed
overview of the course
and practical information.
And that's it.
We hope you enjoy this
DHIS2 Academy course.
(bright music)