(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] In the
last video of the series
about DHIS2 building blocks,
we will discuss the "when"
dimension, the period.
The period is a significant factor
when you are collecting data,
analyzing data over time
or creating periodic reports,
such as monthly, quarterly
or annual aggregated reports.
Let's revisit our example
of new cases of malaria
reported in Namchala Health Center.
We see that those cases were reported
for the period of October of 2020.
That is a very simple example
of a period for aggregate data collection.
In the context of data analysis in DHIS2,
periods can be combined in many ways
and how you use them depends very much
on the type of insight
you are looking for.
You can get aggregated numbers
for a specific period,
such as October of 2020,
month-to-month trend or annual trend.
For example, we might be
interested in malaria data
for this facility displayed
monthly for the last year
to analyze trends.
Or perhaps we are concerned
with yearly aggregate malaria data
for the period of 2016 to 2020.
"Yearly, 2016 to 2020"
and "monthly, last year"
are both examples of periods in DHIS2.
Notice that the first part,
"yearly" or "monthly",
refers to the frequency you would like
to display the data for.
The second part, "last
year" or "2016 to 2020",
refers to the overall timeframe
for which you would like
to aggregate the data.
For data analysis in DHIS2,
any period in DHIS2
will be some combination
of those two components,
frequency and timeframe.
For aggregate data,
the periods available for
you to analyze your data
are dependent upon the predefined period
in which your data are collected.
This depends on the reporting schedule
of a given health program,
which may call for weekly,
monthly, quarterly or annual
reports, among others.
These periods can be configured
for all data collected.
For example, if the data
element, New malaria cases,
is collected monthly,
we can display these data for
each month it is collected
or we can sum these data
to show it by quarter,
six monthly, or yearly.
We would not be able to
show this monthly data
by week, however, as the
lowest level of collection
is by month.
So it cannot be disaggregated any further.
DHIS2 supports two period types
when analyzing or reviewing your data:
fixed periods and relative periods.
October of 2020, or the years 2016 to 2020
are examples of fixed periods,
meaning they refer to a specific
and defined period of time.
DHIS2 also supports relative periods,
such as last year, last
month and this quarter.
These are defined in relation
to the date the analysis is carried out.
In some cases, fixed and
relative periods both refer
to the same period of time.
For example, if the current year is 2021,
then the fixed period, year 2020
and the relative period, last year,
both refer to the same period.
The key difference is that a fixed period
does not update automatically over time
for an analysis item,
whereas the relative period
will automatically update
with new data over time in relation
to the real-world date.
When creating analytical
resources within DHIS2,
it is possible to make
use of this functionality.
Relative periods can be useful
if you want to design a monthly report
that can be reused every month
without having to
manually change the report
to reset the period to the correct month.
In summary, we learned that the period
is the time dimension in DHIS2
for both data collection
and data analysis.
Periods within DHIS2 consist
of a combination of frequency,
such as monthly and yearly,
and a timeframe, such
as 2020, 2016 to 2020
and last six months.
The set frequency of the data collected
defines the lowest level of period detail
that can be performed in data analysis.
While aggregate data capture
uses only fixed periods,
in data analysis, two
types of periods are used:
fixed and relative.
Unlike fixed periods,
which do not update
automatically over time,
relative periods will update
automatically over time
based on the current date of analysis.
(lively music)