(bright music)
- [Instructor] In the previous video,
you learned that any
data value in DHIS2 has
at least three dimensions
associated with it.
The what, the where, and the when.
In this video, we are going to talk
about the where dimension
or organization units.
What is an organization unit?
In simple terms, organization
units represent the location
or the larger geographical
context of the data.
Examples of organization units
include a health facility,
school, location where
services are provided,
or an administrative unit
representing a geographical area,
such as a province or a region.
For example, in Lao, a country
whose Ministry of Health uses
DHIS2, the highest level,
or the root organization
unit, is the country.
The country is further
divided into 18 provinces.
And each of those is subdivided
into smaller districts.
At the lowest level,
you will find individual health facilities
where the data are collected.
Together, all of the organization units
form a hierarchical tree.
In Lao's case, the
hierarchy has four levels
which correspond to the
administrative system.
The structure of the hierarchy,
including the number of
levels, is fully customizable
in DHIS2 to adapt to
each country's context.
Organization units determine
where data can be captured
and how they can be
aggregated or disaggregated
within various reporting outputs.
For example, all data
entered at the facility level
could be aggregated to
provide a total value
for the entire district.
This principle is the same
as you move up the hierarchy.
During the aggregation
process, data are added up
from the lower organization
unit levels to the higher ones.
DHIS2 performs these
calculations automatically.
Organization units also allow
you to display your data
in the DHIS2 Maps application
to better geographically
understand your data.
DHIS2 also allows classifying
organization units
by different criteria
other than the main
administrative hierarchy.
We can do this by using
organization unit groups
and organization unit group sets.
An organization unit group allows
for additional subclassifications
of organization units.
For example, we can create
a parallel classification
of health facilities if
we group them by type,
such as district hospital
or field clinics;
by the form of ownership,
such as public or private;
or by location, such as urban or rural.
This is defined for each specific context
and will be different
from country to country.
Let's have a look at an example
of classification by the type of facility.
In this example, health
facilities are classified
and clustered by the range
of services they provide
into various organization unit groups.
These groups include
dispensary, health center,
specialist hospital,
and referral hospital.
The organization unit
group set is the name
for the umbrella classification
that these individual groups fall under.
In this example, the group
set is type of facility,
a category that contains the
organization unit groups,
which in turn each contains
specific facilities.
Organization unit groups and
group sets are quite useful
for disaggregating data in our analysis.
In this example, we disaggregated data
from malaria positive tests
by the type of facility
to see the trend for
each group separately,
and to compare monthly data
from each type of facility,
making it easier to uncover
potential variations
between them.
In summary, organization units provide
geographical context to data.
In DHIS2, organization units
are hierarchically related
to each other, with each level reflecting
the administrative system
of the country or region.
The organization unit hierarchy
also enables data aggregation.
Data that are collected
at the facility levels
are aggregated upward to higher
level administrative units,
like districts or regions.
DHIS2 also allows classifying
organization units
by different criteria,
such as facility type,
by using organization
unit groups and group sets
to facilitate more nuanced data analysis.
(gentle upbeat music)