(smooth music)
- [Instructor] Once we have data entered into the platform,
how can we check the data&#39;s accuracy and reliability?
In this video, we will explore several tools
in the DHIS2 data quality app that will help us to review
and improve the quality of our data.
First, in the data quality app,
you can run a validation rule analysis
which tests validation rules
against the data registered in the system.
After running the check, you will get a report
with a list of data that need to be checked.
For example, if we look at the first row,
our validation rule says that the value of registered
for the third anti-natal care visit, or ANC,
can not be higher
than the value registered for the second ANC visit.
But the value registered for ANC3 is six,
while the value for ANC2 is four.
We can follow up with this location
to determine the specific source of the error.
Note that you can also run the validation rule analysis
during the data entry process.
The standard deviation outlier analysis
is another tool we can use to check data quality,
identifying those values that are potential outliers
when compared to the standard normal distribution
of the data under review.
Like in the validation rule analysis,
when we run a standard deviation outlier analysis,
we get a report with all the data that need to be checked.
For example, in this row,
the data indicate that only five BCG vaccines were given
in this health facility.
This value of five
falls outside the normal distribution of these data,
and it has been identified as a potential source of error.
Another tool is the min-max outlier analysis,
which checks if the data are within a predefined range
that has been specified for them.
This lists the values that are out of this predefined range.
We can see in the example,
a value of 45 AEFI suspected cases,
which is out of the range
of a minimum of zero to a maximum of 22.
The fourth and last tool available in the data quality app
is the follow-up analysis tool.
Follow-up analysis creates a list of all data values
marked for follow-up.
We can mark a data value for follow-up in the data entry app
and the data quality app
via the reports from the standard deviation outlier
and min-max outlier analysis tools.
This is an example of the report obtained
after running followup analysis in DHIS2.
In coordination with WHO,
a data quality tool for DHIS2 has been created.
This app generates findings on data quality
following WHO&#39;s data quality review framework.
This includes completeness.
That is, if all the expected data are recorded,
timeliness, or if the data were received on time,
internal consistency,
which compares internally submitted data with one another,
and external consistency,
which compares the data with other sources, such as surveys.
As an example, we can review internal consistency.
The WHO data quality tool
allows us to identify outliers within our data.
We can see an example of this in District C-1,
where the number of measles vaccines given in January, 2020
is much higher in comparison to the other values reported
within the same district in the same year.
This helps us easily visualize
what data need to be double-checked
before running any analysis.
In summary, in DHIS2,
there are several tools
that help us to check the quality of the data entered,
such as validation rules,
standard deviation outlier analysis,
minimum-maximum outlier analysis,
and follow up analysis.
DHIS2 and WHO have also collaborated
to create a data quality tool
that runs checks to validate completeness,
timeliness, internal consistency, and external consistency.
(smooth music)