(mellow music)
- DHIS2 is a product
of the Health Information
Systems Programme known as HISP.
HISP is a global action research network
initiated jointly by
the University of Oslo
and the University of the Western Cape
in South Africa in 1994,
with funding from the Norwegian Agency
for Development Cooperation, Norad.
As a result of the HISP collaboration,
the District Health
Information Software or DHIS,
was launched in South Africa in 1996,
starting in one district and becoming
their national standard health
information system in 1999.
From its initial conception,
the core aim of DHIS2 has been
to support local management
of healthcare delivery
and information flow
in low and middle income countries.
To that end, we share our software,
DHIS2 globally as a digital public good.
The original DHIS software
functioned using local offline databases,
but this resulted in
challenges in aggregating
and sharing data,
as well as scaling up
implementations over time.
As a result, in 2004,
development of a web-based DHIS2
began at the University of Oslo.
As DHIS2 is web-based,
users can enter and access their data
anywhere with internet connectivity.
This model is still
being expanded upon today
as DHIS2 incorporates the
latest web-based technologies
to improve DHIS2's performance,
and increase its functionality.
This includes offline data entry for areas
with internet connectivity challenges,
and the incorporation
of a mobile application
for Android devices.
The first implementation
of the web-based DHIS2
software was launched in 2006
in Kerala, India.
In 2009, DHIS2 added
components that allowed
for the collection of individual data.
This was in direct response
to requirements in Kerala,
where prospective mothers were tracked
through their anti-natal care services.
This individual data model
eventually evolved into DHIS2 Tracker.
2007, saw the first
implementation of DHIS2 in Africa,
starting with Sierra Leone.
This was followed in 2010
by Kenya, then Ghana,
Rwanda and Uganda.
In 2011, the DHIS2 Academy
training program began.
The University of Oslo in
collaboration with HISP groups,
offers regional DHIS2 academies every year
on key DHIS2 topics.
Since 2017, the university has also run
the DHIS2 Online Academy,
which provides online courses
for self-paced studying.
In 2012 and 2013, adoption of
DHIS2 as a national platform
for routine health information
continued in Africa,
Asia, and Latin America,
was support from Norad,
the global fund and PEPFAR.
In 2014, the HISP network
assisted health authorities
in Liberia in deploying DHIS2 Tracker
for the Ebola outbreak response.
With the support
of the U.S. Centers for
Disease Control and Prevention,
the Gates Foundation,
Gavi, and other partners,
the initial tracker models
deployed in Liberia,
have since been expanded upon
for case-based surveillance
of other diseases, including COVID-19.
In 2015, DATIM was launched,
a PEPFAR specific version of DHIS2.
DATIM is used by PEPFAR
in more than 50 countries.
DATIM continues to be one
of the largest examples
of a global data warehouse within DHIS2.
Sharing standards and
collating subnational HIV data
routinely across large
and varied geographies.
In 2007, UiO became an official
World Health Organization
collaborating center for innovation
and implementation research
for health information
system strengthening.
This collaboration led to
the metadata package concept;
a method of sharing best
practice configuration
and functionality developed by DHIS2
and health subject matter experts.
2018, saw the DHIS2
community of practice launch,
providing an online portal
to help the community
of DHIS2 practitioners to
connect with each other
and share best practice globally.
2019, saw DHIS2 being piloted
as an Education Management
Information System
in the Gambia and Uganda,
extending the use of DHIS2
into the education domain
for school and infrastructure management,
student tracking and more.
In 2020, DHIS2 was quickly adopted
to combat the COVID-19 pandemic.
The University of Oslo
worked with the HISP network
to launch COVID-19 metadata packages
that allowed countries to rapidly
implement case-based
surveillance, contact tracing,
and ports of entry programs.
In 2021, new metadata
packages were released
to support the delivery
of COVID-19 vaccines,
based on previous work,
developing the DHIS2 immunization toolkit
with the support of WHO, UNICEF,
and Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance.
DHIS2 continues to evolve,
thanks to the work of the core
DHIS2 team and HISP network.
The support of our international partners
and the input of the
global DHIS2 community,
who helped sustain DHIS2
as a global public good,
that can adapt to meet the
health information needs
of the future.
(calm music)